<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 1. Project management basics on BK HQV</title>
    <link>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 1. Project management basics on BK HQV</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I. Introduction into projects</title>
      <link>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/I/</guid>
      <description>1. Concept, overview of project - historical projects 2. Origin and etymology of the word &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo; 3. Project synonyms Synonyms Related words 4. Definition of project 5. Characteristics of projects 6. Other common characteristics of projects 7. This is not a project 8. Project stakeholders 9. Reasons for success or failure of projects Reasons for failure Reasons for success 10. How to prepare a project: 1. Concept, overview of project - historical projects Flag Tower of Hanoi The tower was built in 1812 during the Nguyen dynasty as an observation post to the Hanoi Citadel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>II. Classification of projects</title>
      <link>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/II/</guid>
      <description>1. Based on the fundamentals: term Long term (Years) Short term (Months) 2. Based on the fundamentals: type Strategic project Tactical project 3. According to the source of fund 4. According to foreign aided project 5. According to technique 6. According to function Disaster prevention projects Development projects Abstract 2 main project components. 7. Service sector project 8. According to scale and size 9. According to time frame and speed 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Representative project examples</title>
      <link>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uni.delnegend.com/ProjectManagement/Part1/III/</guid>
      <description>1. University for Science and Technology of Ha Noi (USTH) Bologna Process 2. Loan project ADB 3. Disaster Prevention Project in Vietnam 1. University for Science and Technology of Ha Noi (USTH) The Bilateral project for Education and Training based on Inter-governmental Agreement between Vietnam and France: &amp;ldquo;Establishment and Development of University for Science and Technology of Ha Noi&amp;rdquo; Bologna Process The Bologna Process is an intergovernmental higher education reform process that includes 49 European countries and a number of European organizations, including EUA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
